

Ramin Rezaei

Front-end Engineer

CONTACT

<u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>GitHub</u> | <u>Stack Overflow</u> | <u>Personal Web Page</u>

Tehran, Iran | <u>+989136266179</u> | <u>Ramin.Rezaei77@gmail.com</u>

SUMMARY

I used to be a graphic designer but then I fell in love with programming. I am currently a **front-end engineer** with more than **4 years** of experience and a little bit of back-end development. And now I work for **Digikala**. which is the largest online store in Iran with about 9 million visits per day. Digikala is an Iranian example for Amazon.

I love solving bugs and problems and I like creating web pages whit new ideas. I really believe that nothing is more important and exciting than **learning** and **teaching** web-based technologies and there is still so much for me to learn. I am incredibly patient and friendly with my co-workers and teammates and socialize well with people. Basically, if you have some coffee or Nescafe, I can work with you!

SKILLS

→ Front-end: **JavaScript**, **ReactJS**, Html, CSS, SASS, LESS, Tailwind, NextJs, TypeScript, StoryBook, Jest, E2E testing with Cypress, Prop-Types, JQuery, A/B testing, and familiar with VueJs.

Also, I worked with: Redux, Redux Toolkit, Lodash, Formik, SwiperJs, Material UI, AntDesign, Socket IO, and MapBox.

- → Back-end: **Python** (Django), familiar whit PHP (Laravel), SQL, MySQL, Rest API, Docker, and familiar with NestJs.
- → Others: Git, Linux OS, Scrum, Trunk-based Development (TBD), GitFlow, Prettier, ESlint, Husky, WebPack.

GRAPHIC SKILLS

Adobe Photoshop, Adobe AfterEffects, Adobe Premiere Pro, Motion Graphic Animation, Video Editing. Also, I am familiar with: Cinema 4D, AutoDesk 3Ds Max, Adobe XS, Figma, and Zeplin.

EXPERIENCE

Digikala, Tehran, Iran — Front-end Engineer

August 2020 - Present

JavaScript, TypeScript, ReactJs, NextJs, Redux, Tailwind, SASS, StoryBook, Jest, Cypress, Formik, A/B tests

Digikala is an Iranian e-commerce company based in Tehran. It has 30 million monthly visitors and about 9 million daily visitors. It is also ranked by Alexa as the third most visited website in Iran. Digikala is the Iranian example of the Amazon website in Iran.

- Worked in a highly collaborative agile team environment.
- Wrote unit tests for utils and base components with jest and react-testing-library.
- Wrote end-to-end (E2E) tests for the main flows on the site like add-to-cart, and payment with Cypress.

- Suggested and created a new algorithm and new service for tracking products and banners on the site with Google Analytics functions (DataLayers).
- Designed a new pattern for the API structure presented in the project, which helps to make faster changes in a large system and can assure the client of the existence of information.
- Designed and developed a service to automatically show and hide features and different parts of the site on demo and production versions. This service can activate a part of the site exclusively for certain users or display it to users at a certain time.
- Reducing the reuse of Google Analytics codes and functions by 80% by writing a wrapper and using functions at the lowest level of components.
- Creating a structure to change and verify API data of this software layer helps us to have a cleaner and more readable code.
- 10% improvement in product page load speed and 30% reduction in API requests by caching data, reusing static information, and removing static requests.
- Wrote custom hooks for various tasks on the site. For example: checking the display of an element on the page, reading page size changes, and displaying repetitive information from Redux.
- Increased website view limit by 5x in promotions by rewriting the website with react.
- Reduced bundle size by half due to tree shaking and rewrote of 3rd party libraries.
- 50% performance increase in tracking user behavior with products and banners inside the site.
- Performed code reviews of other team members' work and recommended changes to improve code quality.

SnappCarFix, Esfahan, Iran — Head of Front-end Team

May 2019 – August 2020

JavaScript, ReactJs, Redux, SASS, AntDesign, Google Map, MapBox

SnappCarFix is an online platform for Car parts and services, backed by Snapp (Uber clone). It includes web apps for Stores, service centers, Agents, and Sellers, to offer products/services like oil, battery, engine parts, car wash, etc, with 7 delivery/service solutions per product.

- Created 4 progressive web applications and two admin dashboards.
- Using Google Recaptcha to authenticate site users and using JWT and token refresh in front-end requests.
- Used standard versioning (x,y,z) for projects and automatic update of the client-side cache by version changes.
- Designing a single layout for the organization's sales sites. With this template, it is possible to create a complete and new site in just one day.
- Designed a structure for components that helps to use fewer styles and to be accessible and modified for the styles related to each individual component. In this way, the changes move much faster and it is easy to make big changes in the whole project.
- Increased the Lottie animations performance by 80% by developing a new wrapper.
- Correct use of CSS animation and correct animation of elements on the web and creating high speed and removing lag in the mobile version.
- 60% improvement in SwiperJs performance by writing a wrapper in the project and using it a lot in the whole project without loss of performance.
- Making time-consuming components with high performance and high usage for promotions and discounts on the site and not affecting the user experience.
- Creating identical and changeable components for different projects and increasing the speed of development and change in the organization.
- Restructured the platform from WordPress to React, and handled more requests, with better UI/UX, and fewer development hassles.

Self Employed, Esfahan, Iran — *Freelance*

January 2019 – Present

JavaScript, ReactJs, Redux, Tailwind, SASS, Jest, Python - Django, PHP - Laravel Adobe Photoshop, Adobe After Effects, Adobe Premiere Pro

Apart from my main job, I am involved with various people and in my spare time, I do web projects as well as video editing projects and make motion graphics animations.

EDUCATION

Najaf Abad University, Isfahan — Bachelor's degree

Teacher's assistant for more than 3 courses in 3 semesters.

LANGUAGES

Persian - Native

English - General level

Visit my **LinkedIn** to read what others have to say about me.